Guide to the Horticultural Society of New York Records 1811-circa 2010 (bulk, 1900-circa 2010) MS 3033
New-York Historical Society
- Series I. General Administration Files, 1900-2007; 205779; 20.92 Linear feet
  - Subseries I.C. Executive Directors' Files, 1960s-1990s; 206072; 8.63 Linear feet
    - Exhibitors: B (2 folders), 1970s-1980s; 211455 (Offsite-box 35, Folder 9-10)
      Becker-Wegeli, Friedy
      Bernadotte, Lennart
      Bleicken, Janet
      Bolt, Carolyn
      Bothwell, Mary
      Bronson, Emerick
      Brown, John
      Bushnell, Ken
    - Exhibitors: C-E, 1970s-1980s; 211456 (Offsite-box 35, Folder 11)
      Cameron, Elizabeth
      Conzo, James
      Dowden, Anne Ophelia
      Echols, Margit
      Egee, Marjorie
    - Exhibitors: F, 1970s-1980s; 211457 (Offsite-box 35, Folder 12)
      Fenn, Patricia
      Fong, Constance Tang
      Freedman, Eric
      Friedman, Dolores
    - Exhibitors: G-H, 1970s-1980s; 211458 (Offsite-box 35, Folder 13)
      Grant, Karen Lee
      Grundy, Jane
      Guilliatt, Lee
      Hildebrand, June
      Hubbard, Celia
    - Exhibitors: J-L, 1970s-1980s; 211459 (Offsite-box 36, Folder 1)
      Jordon, Shelley
      Katz, Michael
      Keane, Bob
      Key, Pat
      Lawford, Valentine
      Loewer, H. Peter
    - Exhibitors: M-R, 1970s-1980s; 211460 (Offsite-box 36, Folder 2)
      Mintzer, Judi
      Moynihan, Helen S.
      Nicolary, Kevin
      Pastorelli, Mario
      Phillips, Susan
      Rokach, Allen
      Rosenthal, Roberta
    - Exhibitors: S-T, 1970s-1980s; 211461 (Offsite-box 36, Folder 3)
      Sabarese, Anita
      Scheeline, Lanette
      Scott, Roberta
      Sticht, Rosemary
      Sudran, Deborah
      Tcherepnine, Jessica
    - Exhibitors: W-Z, 1970s-1980s; 211462 (Offsite-box 36, Folder 4)
      Walsh, Janet B.
      Walworth, Joseph
      Wolf, Louise Lindenmeyr (sister of Henry Lindenmeyr III)
      Yang, John
      Zerner, Charles
    - Facilities: Floor plans, general, 1970s; 211409 (Offsite-box 36, Folder 5)
    - Facilities: Floor plans, library, 1970s; 211567 (Offsite-box 36, Folder 6)
    - Facilities: Floor plans, office, 1960s-1970s; 211568 (Offsite-box 36, Folder 7)
    - Facilities: Floor plans, Webster Hall, [1970s?]; 211569 (Offsite-box 36, Folder 8)
    - Facilities: Greenhouse (shop), 1992-1993; 211570 (Offsite-box 36, Folder 9)
    - Facilities: Leases (2 folders), 1960s-1990s; 211572 (Offsite-box 36, Folder 10-11)
    - Facilities: Relocation, 1969; 211573 (Offsite-box 36, Folder 12)
    - Facilities: Renovations (3 folders), 1950s-1980s; 211574 (Offsite-box 36, Folder 13-15)
    - Facilities: General (5 folders), 1950s-1990s; 211416 (Offsite-box 36, Folder 16-20)
    - Financial: Insurance, 1940s-1990s; 211582 (Offsite-box 37, Folder 1)
    - Financial: Treasurer's reports & tax exemptions, 1940s-1970s; 211583 (Offsite-box 37, Folder 2)
    - Flower shows: Bryant Park, 1971-1972; 211403 (Offsite-box 37, Folder 3)
    - Flower shows: International Flower Show (possibility), 1970; 211585 (Offsite-box 37, Folder 4)
    - Flower shows: New York Flower Show (2 folders), 1984-1990; 211586 (Offsite-box 37, Folder 5-6)
    - Flower shows: New York Flower Show tickets (2 folders), 1980s; 211587 (Offsite-box 37, Folder 7-8)
    - Flower shows: Rockefeller Center, 1994; 211588 (Offsite-box 37, Folder 9)
    - Fundraising: Correspondence & appeals (2 folders), 1960s-1980s; 211596 (Offsite-box 37, Folder 10-11)
    - Fundraising: Contributions (3 folders), 1960s-1990s; 211597 (Offsite-box 37, Folder 12-14)
    - Fundraising: General, 1990-1993; 211599 (Offsite-box 37, Folder 15)
    - Fundraising: Linnaean Fellows, 1967-1972; 211408 (Offsite-box 109, Box FF-8)
    - Fundraising: The Book of Trees, 1967-1972; 213281 (Offsite-box 112, Box FF-12)
      List of donors and amounts pledged to "A Tree for New York" tree-planting program. Includes price list and tree symbolism (e.g., linden = fidelity; ginko = longevity; etc.)
    - Library, 1991-1993; 211443 (Offsite-box 38, Folder 4)
    - Membership & mailing lists, 1970s-1990s; 211442 (Offsite-box 38, Folder 5)
    - Master plans, 1981-1982; 211410 (Offsite-box 38, Folder 6)
    - Master plan (3 folders), 1983-1992; 211552 (Offsite-box 38, Folder 7-9)
    - Master plan: Activities, 1982-1993; 211553 (Offsite-box 38, Folder 10)
    - Mission statements, 1970s-1996; 211554 (Offsite-box 38, Folder 11)
    - Operational, 1980s-1990s; 211431 (Offsite-box 38, Folder 12)
    - Press Clippings, 1970s-1990s; 211555 (Offsite-box 38, Folder 13-14)
    - Public Relations, 1970s-1990s; 211407 (Offsite-box 38, Folder 15)
    - Programs, beautification: Adam Clayton Powell Boulevard, 1985; 211561 (Offsite-box 38, Folder 16)
    - Programs, beautification: Community Gardens, 1970s-1980s; 211563 (Offsite-box 38, Folder 17)
    - Programs, beautification: Cooper-Hewitt, 1980-1982; 211562 (Offsite-box 38, Folder 18)
    - Programs, beautification: Fall Harvest Festival, 1982-1983; 211564 (Offsite-box 38, Folder 19)
    - Programs, beautification: Gracie Mansion grounds (2 folders), 1980s; 211411 (Offsite-box 39, Folder 1-2)
    - Programs, beautification: Lincoln West, 1980s; 211556 (Offsite-box 39, Folder 3)
    - Programs, beautification: New York Cares, 1993; 211557 (Offsite-box 39, Folder 4)
    - Programs, beautification: NYC Bicentennial, 1973; 211558 (Offsite-box 39, Folder 5)
    - Programs, beautification: Port-a-Park, 1970s-1980s; 211559 (Offsite-box 39, Folder 6)
    - Programs, beautification: Trees, 1970s-1990s; 211560 (Offsite-box 39, Folder 7)
    - Programs, educational: General (3 folders), 1970s-1990s; 211419 (Offsite-box 39, Folder 8-10)
    - Programs, educational: Apple Seed, 1992-1993; 211490 (Offsite-box 39, Folder 11)
    - Programs, educational: Children's Horticulture Program at Queens Botanical Garden, 1973; 211547 (Offsite-box 39, Folder 12)
    - Programs, educational: City-as-School, 1972; 211546 (Offsite-box 39, Folder 13)
    - Programs, educational: Compleat Gardener, 1990s; 211491 (Offsite-box 39, Folder 14)
    - Programs, educational: Cornell Cooperative Extension, 1970s-1980s; 211492 (Offsite-box 39, Folder 15)
    - Programs, educational: Cornell New York City Gardening Program, 1970s; 211493 (Offsite-box 39, Folder 16)
    - Programs, educational: Courses, various; 211494 (Offsite-box 39, Folder 17)
    - Programs, educational: Department of Youth Services, 1992; 211495 (Offsite-box 39, Folder 18)
    - Programs, educational: Great Cookie Lesson, 1993; 211496 (Offsite-box 39, Folder 19)
    - Programs, educational: Greenworks, 1992-1993; 211497 (Offsite-box 39, Folder 20)
    - Programs, educational: Harlem Project, 1992-1994; 211498 (Offsite-box 39, Folder 21)
    - Programs, educational: Horticulture Magazine Lecture Series, 1992-1993; 211499 (Offsite-box 39, Folder 22)
    - Programs, educational: House Plant Course, 1970s; 211545 (Offsite-box 39, Folder 23)
    - Programs, educational: Project Oasis, 1993; 211500 (Offsite-box 39, Folder 24)
    - Programs, educational: Rooftop Gardens, 1988; 211501 (Offsite-box 39, Folder 25)
    - Programs, educational: Arthur Sheppard Programs, 1983-1987; 211502 (Offsite-box 39, Folder 26)
    - Programs, educational: Street Fairs, 1993; 211503 (Offsite-box 39, Folder 27)
    - Programs, educational: Harriet Tubman Center, 1993-1993; 211504 (Offsite-box 39, Folder 28)
    - Programs: Ideas, possibilities, 1970s-1990s; 211550 (Offsite-box 39, Folder 29)
    - Special events: General (2 folders), 1980s-1995; 211398 (Offsite-box 40, Folder 1-2)
    - Special events: Annual Awards Luncheon, 1970s; 211506 (Offsite-box 40, Folder 3)
    - Special events: Battery Park Tour / Party, 1993 September 8; 211507 (Offsite-box 40, Folder 4)
    - Special events: Colony Club Luncheon, 1993 September 23; 211508 (Offsite-box 40, Folder 5)
    - Special events: Harvest Ball, 1993; 211509 (Offsite-box 40, Folder 6)
    - Special events: Enid Annenberg (Mrs. Ira) Haupt, 1970s; 211510 (Offsite-box 40, Folder 7)
    - Special events: Leland Hayward Benefit, 1978; 211511 (Offsite-box 40, Folder 8)
    - Special events: Raffle Ideas, 1995; 211512 (Offsite-box 40, Folder 9)
    - Special events: Reception, 1994 June 13; 211513 (Offsite-box 40, Folder 10)
    - Special events: Receptions, 1970s; 211514 (Offsite-box 40, Folder 11)
    - Special events: Republic National Bank, 1993; 211515 (Offsite-box 40, Folder 12)
    - Special events: Spring Party (Sea Grill), 1994 April 11; 211516 (Offsite-box 40, Folder 13)
    - Staff, 1970s-1990s; 211399 (Offsite-box 40, Folder 14)
    - Subject Files (3 folders), 1970s-1990s; 211606 (Offsite-box 40, Folder 15-17)
      Conservatory Gardens
      Concil on the Environment
      Earth Day '95
      Ellis Island
      Environmental Construction Organization
      Fresh Start
      Garden Club of America
      Garden Conservancy
      Garden Magazine (correspondence)
      Gateway National Park
      Land Trusts
      Marie Selby Botanical Garden
      National Wildlife Research Center
      New York State Department of Agriculture and Marketing
      Royal Horticultural Society
      Seatuck
      Sleepy Hollow Restoration
      Sotheby's
      Miscellany
    - Trips & tours: General, 1970s; 211396 (Offsite-box 40, Folder 18)
    - Trips & tours: General, 1990s; 211489 (Offsite-box 40, Folder 19)
    - Trips & tours: Costa Rica, 1978; 211479 (Offsite-box 40, Folder 20)
    - Trips & tours: England (3 folders), 1970s-1980s; 211480 (Offsite-box 40, Folder 21-23)
    - Trips & tours: France, 1983-1984; 211482 (Offsite-box 40, Folder 24)
    - Trips & tours: Hawaii (3 folders), 1971; 211483 (Offsite-box 41, Folder 1-3)
    - Trips & tours: Ireland, 1986-1987; 211484 (Offsite-box 41, Folder 4)
    - Trips & tours: Italy, 1995-1996; 211485 (Offsite-box 41, Folder 5)
    - Trips & tours: Portugal, 1973; 211486 (Offsite-box 41, Folder 6)
    - Trips & tours: Puerto Rico, 1973; 211487 (Offsite-box 41, Folder 7)
    - Trips & tours: U.S. Virgin Islands, 1973; 211488 (Offsite-box 41, Folder 8)
    - Webster, Charles D. (2 folders), 1960s-1990s; 211578 (Offsite-box 41, Folder 9-10)
  - Subseries I.D. Presidents' Files, 1930s-1990s (bulk, 1990s); 211387; 2.5 Linear feet
    Subseries I.D encompasses the administrative files of the HSNY President's office. They are chiefly Millicent Johnson's, who held the title in the 1990s, but possibly include material from others. Like Subseries I.E, these administrative documents are grouped by topic, rather than creator.
    - Awards, 1990s; 211702 (Offsite-box 41, Folder 11)
    - Board of Directors: Meetings, 1990s; 211703 (Offsite-box 41, Folder 12)
    - Board of Directors: Minutes, 1994-1996; 211704 (Offsite-box 41, Folder 13)
    - Board of Directors: Committees, 1990s; 211741 (Offsite-box 41, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence, 1990s; 211705 (Offsite-box 41, Folder 15)
    - Development, 1990s; 211706 (Offsite-box 41, Folder 16)
    - Executive Director: Barbara Earnest, 1994-1996; 211708 (Offsite-box 41, Folder 17)
    - Executive Director: Search (2 folders), 1993-1996; 211707 (Offsite-box 41, Folder 18-19)
    - Exhibitions & Exhibitors, 1990s; 211709 (Offsite-box 42, Folder 1)
    - Facilities, 1997; 211710 (Offsite-box 42, Folder 2)
    - Facilities: Leases, 1990s; 211711 (Offsite-box 42, Folder 3)
    - Financial: General (3 folders), 1990s; 211712 (Offsite-box 42, Folder 4-6)
    - Financial: Endowment, 1990s; 211743 (Offsite-box 42, Folder 7)
    - Financial: Reports, 1989-2000; 211745 (Offsite-box 42, Folder 8)
    - Flower Shows: New York Flower Show expenses, 1985-1993; 211767 (Offsite-box 42, Folder 9)
    - Flower Shows: 1990 New York Flower Show, 211713 (Offsite-box 42, Folder 10)
    - Flower Shows: 1991 New York Flower Show, 211770 (Offsite-box 42, Folder 11)
    - Flower Shows: 1992 New York Flower Show, 211771 (Offsite-box 42, Folder 12)
    - Flower Shows: 1993 New York Flower Show, 211772 (Offsite-box 42, Folder 13)
    - Flower Shows: 1995 New York Flower Show (2 folders), 211773 (Offsite-box 42, Folder 14-15)
    - Flower Shows: 1996 New York Flower Show (3 folders), 211774 (Offsite-box 42, Folder 16-18)
    - Flower Shows: 1997 New York Flower Show, 211775 (Offsite-box 42, Folder 19)
    - Flower Shows: Rockefeller Center Flower Show, 1997; 211714 (Offsite-box 42, Folder 20)
    - Fundraising: Appeals, 1990s; 211715 (Offsite-box 42, Folder 21)
    - Fundraising: Contributions, 1990s; 211716 (Offsite-box 43, Folder 1)
    - Fundraising: Foundations & Trusts, 1990s; 211742 (Offsite-box 43, Folder 2)
    - Fundraising: John O'Donnell, 1990s; 211717 (Offsite-box 43, Folder 3)
    - Invitations, 1990s; 211718 (Offsite-box 43, Folder 4)
    - IT, 1994; 211720 (Offsite-box 43, Folder 5)
    - Library, 1990s; 211721 (Offsite-box 43, Folder 6)
    - Membership, 1990s-2000; 211722 (Offsite-box 43, Folder 7)
    - Mission & Constitution (2 folders), 1930s-1990s; 211723 (Offsite-box 43, Folder 8-9)
    - Operational, [1990s]; 211724 (Offsite-box 43, Folder 10)
    - Press Clippings, 1990s; 211725 (Offsite-box 43, Folder 11)
    - Programs, beautification: Green Branches, 1990s; 211728 (Offsite-box 43, Folder 12)
    - Programs, beautification: Metrotech, 1990s; 211792 (Offsite-box 43, Folder 13)
    - Programs, beautification: Midtown Community Court, 1990s; 211793 (Offsite-box 43, Folder 14)
    - Programs, educational: Green House (Rikers), 1990s; 211729 (Offsite-box 43, Folder 15)
    - Programs, educational: Green Team, 1990s; 211794 (Offsite-box 43, Folder 16)
    - Programs: General, 1990s; 211748 (Offsite-box 43, Folder 17)
    - Publications, 1990s; 211726 (Offsite-box 43, Folder 18)
    - Public Relations, 1990s; 211727 (Offsite-box 43, Folder 19)
    - Special Events & Benefits: Fall Luncheon, 1990s-2000; 211730 (Offsite-box 43, Folder 20)
    - Special Events & Benefits: Flowers in Design, 1999; 211795 (Offsite-box 43, Folder 21)
    - Special Events & Benefits: Garden Cocktail Party, 1997; 211797 (Offsite-box 43, Folder 22)
    - Special Events & Benefits: Gramercy Garden Antique Show, 2000; 211798 (Offsite-box 43, Folder 23)
    - Special Events & Benefits: HSNY Centennial, 1999; 211799 (Offsite-box 43, Folder 24)
    - Special Events & Benefits: Knickerbocker Benefit, 1993; 211800 (Offsite-box 43, Folder 25)
    - Special Events & Benefits: Spring Party (Sea Grill), 1994 April 11; 211802 (Offsite-box 43, Folder 26)
    - Staff, 1990s; 211731 (Offsite-box 43, Folder 27)
    - Strategic Planning, 1990s; 211732 (Offsite-box 43, Folder 28)
    - Trips & Tours, 1990s; 211733 (Offsite-box 43, Folder 29)
  - Subseries I.E. Miscellaneous, 1933-1984; 211388; 2.88 Linear feet
    The bulk of Subseries I.E regards the 6,000-volume library of botanical books and illustrations bequeathed to the HSNY by lawyer and collector Kenneth K. Mackenzie in 1934. Mackenzie's gift was particularly strong in the works of Swedish botanist and "father of modern taxonomy" Carolus Linnaeus (1707-1778). That portion of the collection--known as the MacKenzie Linnaeana--was acquired by Kansas State University in 1966. The rest of the collection was sold in 1980.
    Subseries I.E also includes HSNY guestbooks and visitor logs for exhibits and the library (1933-2010, with large gaps), and material relating to the proposed Lillian Gish Garden in Manhattan. The latter was the brainchild of landscape designer Luther Greene (1910-1987), who in 1980 received approval from Community Board 6 and the Art Commission of the City of New York to plant a garden--with Horticultural Society of New York assistance--honoring actress and longtime Sutton Place resident Lillian Gish (1893-1993) at the foot of East 56th Street. The site, on a platform over the FDR Drive, remained barren since its creation around 1943. Today it has been absorbed by Sutton Place Park.
    This subseries is split into three groups: guestbooks/visitor logs; Mackenzie Collection; and Lillian Gish Garden. The files in each group are organized chronologically.
    Related Archival Materials Note
    See Subseries II.A. Accession Records, 1926-1989 for additional documentation of the Kenneth K. Mackenzie accession.
    - Guestbook: Exhibits, 1933-1940; 211604 (Offsite-box 109, Box FF-8)
    - Guestbook: Exhibits, 1980 July - 1982 June; 211603 (Offsite-box 37, Folder 16)
    - Guestbook: [Library], 1970-1981; 211600 (Offsite-box 38, Folder 1)
    - Guestbook: Library, 1981-1989; 211601 (Offsite-box 38, Folder 2)
    - Guestbook: [Library], 1990-1995; 211602 (Offsite-box 38, Folder 3A)
    - Visitor Log, 2009-2010; 212222 (Offsite-box 38, Folder 3B)
    - Mackenzie Collection: Bequest (will), 1934; 212685 (Offsite-box 64, Folder 1)
    - Mackenzie Collection: Biographical, 1930s-1990s; 212686 (Offsite-box 64, Folder 2)
    - Mackenzie Collection: General, 1930s-1960s; 212687 (Offsite-box 64, Folder 3)
    - Mackenzie Collection: Inventory, 1940; 211804 (Offsite-box 64, Folder 4)
    - Mackenzie Collection: Inventory, 1942; 212690 (Offsite-box 64, Folder 5)
    - Mackenzie Collection: Exhibits, 1951-1952; 212647 (Offsite-box 64, Folder 6)
    - Mackenzie Collection: Correspondence, 1953-1963; 212648 (Offsite-box 64, Folder 7)
    - Mackenzie Collection: Exhibits, 1954; 212649 (Offsite-box 64, Folder 8)
    - Mackenzie Collection: Correspondence, 1958-1968; 212650 (Offsite-box 64, Folder 9)
    - Mackenzie Collection: Exhibits, Grolier Club, 1964; 212653 (Offsite-box 64, Folder 10)
    - Mackenzie Collection: Linnaeana sale (2 folders), 1963-1966; 212654 (Offsite-box 64, Folder 11-12)
    - Mackenzie Collection: Catalog promotional material, 1969-1970; 212657 (Offsite-box 64, Folder 13)
    - Mackenzie Collection: Catalog (published volume), 1970; 212655 (Offsite-box 64, Folder 14)
      A copy of Elizabeth Cornelia Hall's Printed Books, 1481-1900 in the Horticultural Society of New York (New York: the Society, 1970), annotated with sale prices for individual titles.
    - Mackenzie Collection: Catalog supplements, n.d.; 212656 (Offsite-box 64, Folder 15)
    - Mackenzie Collection: Sale (correspondence), 1977-1980; 212658 (Offsite-box 64, Folder 16)
    - Mackenzie Collection: Sale (correspondence), 1977-1982; 212659 (Offsite-box 64, Folder 17)
    - Mackenzie Collection: Sale (correspondence), 1979; 212660 (Offsite-box 64, Folder 18)
    - Mackenzie Collection: Sale (correspondence), 1979-1980; 212661 (Offsite-box 64, Folder 19)
    - Mackenzie Collection: New York State Attorney General exhibits (2 folders), 1980; 212662 (Offsite-box 65, Folder 1-2)
    - Mackenzie Collection: Inventory, 1980; 212663 (Offsite-box 65, Folder 3)
    - Mackenzie Collection: Sale & Inventory, 1980; 212664 (Offsite-box 65, Folder 4)
    - Mackenzie Collection: Sale (2 folders), 1980; 212665 (Offsite-box 65, Folder 5-6)
    - Mackenzie Collection: Inventory (2 folders), [1980]; 212666 (Offsite-box 65, Folder 7-8)
    - Mackenzie Collection: Appraisal Prices, [1980]; 212667 (Offsite-box 65, Folder 9)
    - Mackenzie Collection: Sale, 1981; 212668 (Offsite-box 65, Folder 10)
    - Mackenzie Collection: Sale (Christie's), 1997; 212669 (Offsite-box 65, Folder 11)
    - Lillian Gish Garden (2 folders), 1979-1984; 211803 (Offsite-box 65, Folder 12-13)
    - Lillian Gish Garden: Renderings (4 views), 1980; 212584 (Offsite-box 111, Box FF-11, Folder 1)
      Four artistic renderings of the projected landscape design.
- Series II. Library & Archives Files, 1926-circa 2010; 211478; 10.83 Linear feet
  Series II. Library & Archives Files, 1926-circa 2010 is divided into the following subseries:
  Subseries II.A. Accession Records, 1926-1989
  Subseries II.B. Library Committee, 1936-1988
  Subseries II.C. Librarian Files, 1970s-2008
  Subseries II.D. Archives Files, 1930s-circa 2010
  The series includes records concerning the development and administration of the Hort's Library. Among the most important of these records are the Library's accession registers from 1926-1989 and the minutes of the Library Committee from 1936-1974, with related Committee files continuing to 1988. In addition there is a set of Library administration files dating primarily from the 1990s through early 2000s and that generally appear to be those of Librarian Katherine Powis. These administrative files also include some Library Committee and accession documents, as well as files on Library resources, funding, programs, and other matters. The series also includes files related to the Hort's initiative in the 1990s and 2000s to compile their historical records into an archive; these files include both working files about the archive itself and reference files with photocopies, and some originals, of historical documents.
  - Subseries II.A. Accession Records, 1926-1989; 211589; 0.83 Linear feet
    The subseries includes the Library's ledgers recording its accessions from the 1920s through 1989.
    The five ledgers in the subseries are arranged in accession number order.
    - Accessions Ledger 1. #1-5000, 1926-1941; 211590 (Offsite-box 52, Volume 1)
    - Accessions Ledger 2. #5001-10,000, 1935; 211591 (Offsite-box 52, Volume 2)
      All entries relate to the Kenneth K. Mackenzie accession.
    - Accessions Ledger 3. #10,001-15,000, 1935, 1941-1961; 211592 (Offsite-box 53, Volume 1)
      Includes continuation of Mackenzie 1935 accession (10,001-11,000; 14,401-15,000).
    - Accessions Ledger 4. #15,001-20,024, 1961-1980; 211623 (Offsite-box 53, Volume 2)
    - Accessions Ledger 5. #20,025-21,748, 1981-1989; 211626 (Offsite-box 53, Volume 3)
  - Subseries II.B. Library Committee, 1936-1988; 211519; 0.75 Linear feet
    The subseries primarily includes documents related to the periodic meetings of the Library Committee. These documents include the agendas and minutes of the meetings from the 1930s through the late 1980s. Most of these minutes were found in well-ordered binders, into the 1970s. Subsequent to 1974, the files are a mix of minutes and working files related to the meetings. Some of these later files also include documents related to the Library, but not clearly to the Committee. For at least some of the years, the files include summaries of library usage and of accessions.
    The subseries is arranged in roughly chronological order. The first seven folders include the relatively well-focused contents of binders that held meeting minutes from 1936 to 1974. The later folders are somewhat less focused, with a mix of minutes and working files, often from overlapping years.
    - Library Committee Files (16 folders), 1936-1988; 211938 (Offsite-box 54, Folder 1-16)
  - Subseries II.C. Librarian Files, 1970s-2008; 211521; 4.75 Linear feet
    The subseries includes the subject files of Hort Librarian Katherine Powis. Powis joined Hort in January 1989, and she remained as Librarian into the early 2000s; the files in this subseries date primarily from the 1990s to approximately 2005. Powis previously worked as an Assistant Science Librarian at St. John's University, after earning her Masters degree in Library Science from Queens College in 1986.
    Powis's files primarily include various Library administrative matters, especially Library Committee meetings, Library usage statistics, funding (e.g., benefits, grants), donations of books, planning, and bibliographies and other Library resource lists. Some of these administrative files relate to the Library's Archives project (see Subseries II.D) and some concern general Hort administration, such as a copy of an employee handbook and membership lists. The files also include some records related to programs and events, such as the Library's outreach at the annual "New York is Book Country" event, hand-outs for events, program progress reports, and other material.